Finding Aid for the Paul Friedländer Papers, 1848-1976 LSC.1551
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence
  - Stenzel, B(ertha E.), to [Paul] Friedländer,., March 21, 1955; 248.; Typed letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    Removed from Plato manuscript. Summaries of Scholarship IV (H: Helmbold/Holther).
  - Stenzel, Bertha [E.], to [Paul] Friedländer,., April 4, 1955; 249.; Typed letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    Removed from Plato manuscript. Summaries of Scholarship I (G: Godel).
  - Stenzel, Bertha [E.], to [Paul] Friedländer,., February 29, 1956; 250.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    Removed from Plato manuscript. Summaries of Scholarship I (M: Meldrum).
  - Stenzel, Bertha [E.], to [Paul] Friedländer, s.a., 251.; Autograph letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    Removed from Plato manuscript. Summaries of Scholarship II (A: before "A?H?EIA Pindar").
  - Stenzel, [...], to [Paul] Friedländer,., May 20, 1950; 252.; Typed letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    Removed from Plato manuscript. Summaries of Scholarship IV (F: Field, Plato and his Contemporaries [incipit]).
  - [Travis] Al(bert H.), to Fred,., November 6, 1965; 253.; Typed letter signed (1p.). (Box 1)
    See also Offprints and prospectuses, [Travis, Albert H.], Commentariorum Editio Harvardiana Servianorum in Vergilii Carmina, III.
  - University of California, Academic Senate, to Paul Friedländer [sic],., December 5, 1957 (p.m.); 254. (Box 1)
    In box 2, Friedländer, Classical Manuscripts: Unbound, "Virgil."
  - University of California, College of Letters and Science,., April 30, 1962; 245a. (Box 1)
    (Envelope): in box 2, Friedländer, Classical Manuscripts: Unbound, "Aristotle."
  - University of California, Los Angeles, Department of Classics, to [Charlotte] Friedländer [sic],., March 5, 1971 (p.m.); 255.; Envelope. (Box 1)
  - [University of California, Los Angeles, Department of] Classics] to [Charlotte] Friedländer [sic],., April 22, 1971 (p.m.); 256.; Envelope. (Box 1)
  - [University of California, Los Angeles] Emeriti Services Center, to [Charlotte] Friedländer,., July 12, 1972; 257.; Envelope, with "More Life for Your Leafs" 11.6, June 1972;Roll Call;UCLA Emeriti Reporter 2.2, June 1972. (Box 1)
  - Vanselow, A. (Bruckmann, F., A.-G. Verlagsabteilung), to Paul Friedländer,., March 14, 1927; 258.; Typed letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Weizsäcker, Adolf, to Paul Friedländer,., September 15, 1919; 259.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wenzel, H., to Charlotte O. Friedländer,., September 29, 1971; 260.; Typed letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz, Hilde von; Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von; Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, to Paul Friedländer,., January 29, 1918 (p.m.); 261.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitzf-Moellendorff], Marie von, to P[aul] Friedländer,., January 2, 1918; 262.; Typed letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf), envelope. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to Paul Friedländer,., January 29, 1918 (Box 1)
    See Wilamowitz, Hilde von; Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von; Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, to Paul Friedländer, January 29, 1918 (p.m.) Autograph Postcard Signed.
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to [Paul] Friedländer,., June 17, 1918; 263.; Autograph letter signed (4pp., 1 leaf), envelope. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to P[aul] Friedländer,., July 3, 1918 (p.m.); 264.; Envelope. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to [Paul] Friedländer,., August 27, 1926; 265.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to [Paul Friedländer],., [Sept. ca 29, 1931]; 266.; 1p. (2 leaves). (Box 1)
    On acknowledgment from Marie v. Wilamowitz-Moellendorff et al. (printed), September 29, 1931.
  - [Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Marie von], to Paul Friedländer,., December 5, 1931; 267.; Envelope only. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to P[aul] Friedländer,., December 27, 1933; 268.; Typed letter signed (1p.), envelope. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to Paul Friedländer,., December 6, 1934; 269.; TPS. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, to [Paul] Friedländer,., July 3, 1935; 270.; Typed letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    See Wilamowitz File, Wilamowitz at desk.
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von, 271. (Box 1)
    See above, Wilamowitz, Hilde von (January 29, 1918).
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] [Ulrich von], to [Charlotte Friedländer],., December 31, 1921; 272.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to P[aul] Friedländer,., November 4, 1904 (p.m.); 273.; Autograph postcard. (Box 1)
  - Wi(lamowitz-Moellendorff), U(lrich von), to P(aul) Friedländer,., September 28, 1906 (p.m.); 274.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., October 27, 1906; 275.; Autograph letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., November 12, 1906 (p.m.); 276.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf), envelope. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to P[aul] Friedländer,., August 22, 1909 (p.m.); 277.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to Paul Friedländer,., May 31, 1916 (p.m.); 278.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitzf-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., December 12, 1917; 279.; Autograph letter signed (3pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, to Paul Friedländer,., January 29, 1918 (p.m.); 280a.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
    See Wilamowitz, Hilde von; Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], Marie von; Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, to Paul Friedländer, January 29, 1918 (p.m.). Autograph postcard signed.
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(rich von), Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], U[lrich von], to [Paul Friedländer],., July 3, [1918]; 280.; Autograph letter signed (3pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff], U[lrich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., December 20, 1921; 281.; Autograph letter signed (4pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moellendorff] U(lrich von), Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, to Paul Friedländer,., March 31, 1924 (p.m.); 282.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von,., January 1929; 283.; Printed acknowledgment, signed, 1p. (Box 1)
  - [Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von], to Paul Friedländer,., June 18, 1929 (p.m.); 284.; Autograph postcard. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, to [Paul] Friedländer,., July 11, 1929 (p.m.); 285.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
    Removed from Friedländer, Offprints: "Retractiones" Hermes 64, 1929.
  - W(ilamowitz-)M(oellendorff), U(lrich von), to Paul Friedländer,., October 3, 1929 (p.m.); 286.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff) U(lrich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., July 23, 1930; 287.; Autograph letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff] U(rich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., November 4, 1930; 288.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 2 leaves). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff) U(lrich von), to [Paul] Friedländer,., January 9, 1931 (p.m.); 289.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz[-Moeliendorff) U(lrich von), to [Paul] Friedländer,., February 17, 1931 (p.m.); 290.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
    Removed from Friedländer's "Vorklassisch und Nachlassisch" in Das Problem des Klassischen und die Antike (Box 1).
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff), U(lrich von), to Paul Friedländer,., [March 20?, 1931 p.m.]; 291.; Autograph postcard signed (box 3). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff), U(lrich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., April 25, [1931]; 292.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf), envelope [letter and envelope missing]. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff), U(lrich von), to [Paul Friedländer],., July 23, 1931; 293.; Autograph letter signed (1p., 1 leaf) [missing]. (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz(-Moellendorff) U(lrich von), to [Paul] Friedländer,., August 8, 1931; 294.; Autograph postcard signed (box 2). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von, testimonial for [Paul] Friedländer, s.a., 295.; Typed letter copy (1p.). (Box 1)
  - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, Ulrich von (Box 1)
    See also Friedländer, Charlotte, correspondence.
  - Wilcken, Ulrich, to [...],., December 1932; 296.; Printed acknowledgment (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wildenhain, Marguerite, to Paul Friedländer [sic], s.a., 297.; Envelope (stamp removed). (Box 1)
  - Wilkins, Roy (NAACP), to [Mrs. Paul Friedländer],., October 5, 1972; 298.; Form-letter (2pp., 1 leaf) accompanied by three envelopes, "Busing: It's Right," and note. (Box 1)
  - Wolters, [Paul], to [Paul] Friedländer,., June 22, 1924; 299.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Wolters, [Paul], to [Paul] Friedländer,., June 10, 1930; 300.; Autograph letter signed (4pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Zuckmayer, Carl, to "Den Freunden des Haüses Fischer," Weihnachten., 1966; 301.; Mimeograph (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - Zuntz, Günther, to [Paul Friedländer],., September 1, 1928; 302.; Autograph letter signed (1p., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
    Removed from Zuntz's Ueber Hölderlins.
  - ---, Harry and Mary., 303. (Box 1)
    Removed from Lloyd-Jones's Greek Studies.
  - ---, Henri, to Paul [Friedländer],., July 23, 1936; 304. (Box 1)
    Removed from Rilke's Duineser Elegien, 1923).
  - ---, lula, to [Char]lotte [Friedländer],., June 13, 1915; 305.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 2 leaves). (Box 1)
    Envelope: removed from Box 4 (grey folder).
  - ---, lula, to Charlotte [Friedländer],., April 1, 1919; 306.; Autograph letter signed (1p., 1 leaf) with verse "Hohe Gemeinschaft" [etc.] (3 sheets). (Box 1)
    (Removed from [Paul Friedländer?], Poetry notebook, incipit: "Der Kreis Der Liebe," box ---).
  - ---, Marguerite, to Charlotte [Friedländer], s.a., 307.; Autograph card signed, envelope. (Box 1)
  - ---, Marguerite, to [Charlotte Friedländer], s.a., 308.; Autograph card signed, envelope. (Box 1)
  - ---, Martha, to Paul and Charlotte Friedländer [sic], s.a., 309.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - ---, Moriz (?), uncle, to Paul [Friedländer],., January 4, 1917; 310.; Autograph letter signed (8pp., 2 leaves). (Box 1)
  - ---, to [Charlotte] Friedländer,., August 2, 1922 (p.m.); 311.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
    Removed from Leitschuh's Würzburg, 1911 (Box 7).
  - ---, to Charlotte Friedländer,., October 3, 1970 (p.m.); 312.; Typed letter. (Box 1)
    Removed from Bibliothek Paul Friedländer (Box 4).
  - ---, to [Paul Friedländer?],., December 5, 1914; 313.; Autograph letter signed (4pp., 1 leaf). (Box 1)
  - ---, to Paul Friedländer [sic],., January 2, 1957 (p.m.); 314.; Autograph postcard signed. (Box 1)
  - ---, [to Paul Friedländer], s.a., 315.; Autograph letter signed. (Box 1)
  - ---. to [Paul] Friedländer,., July 9, 1933 (p.m.); 316.; Envelope. (Box 1)
- Classical manuscripts
  - Bound Manuscripts
    - "Bibliothek Paul Friedländer.", 317. (Box 2)
    - Bücheler, [Franz], "Theokrit und die sog. Bukolier" and "Interpret, von Plautus' Truculentus" (lecture notes apparently taken by Paul Friedländer)., 318. (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Euripides" Winter Semester 1917/18 (lecture notes: some blank leaves torn from center); one loose leaf incipit: "po???? (nicht po?o?).", 319. (Box 2)
    - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, U(lrich) v(on), "Die drei griechischen Tragiker" (lecture notes apparently taken by Paul Friedländer)., 320. (Box 2)
    - Wilamowitz-Moellendorff, U(lrich) v(on), "Pindaros" (lecture notes apparently taken by Paul Friedländer)., (October 26, 1900- ); 321. (Box 2)
  - Unbound Manuscripts etc.
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Aristotle" (lecture notes)., 322.; (22 pieces + envelope). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Greco-Egyptian Tapestries of Late antiquity.", 323.; (19 pieces + envelope). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Greek Democracy, November 1941" (lecture notes)., 324.; (15pp.). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Greek 42A" (notes for lectures/book)., 325.; (40 pieces + envelope). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Lucan.", 326.; (32 fragments + envelope). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Platons Werke W.S. 1928/9" (lecture notes)., 327.; (ca. 65 leaves). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Virgil" (lecture notes)., 328.; (53 leaves + envelope). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], Fy 153 | Socr. PL | AR" (lecture notes)., 329.; (98 pieces + envelope). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], Miscellaneous classical papers., 330.; (6 pieces). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], Miscellaneous classical and scholarly papers., 331.; (6 pieces). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], Notes on "Grundzüge der Geschichte des Herakles-Mythos"; "Verklassisch und Nachklassisch"; autobiographical note ("Ich was zuletzt Krank")., 332.; (12 leaves and folder). (Box 2)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], Notes on Jaeger's Paideia., 333.; II (4pp.) **(pp.1-3 and ts). (Box 2)
      Note: p.2 was with the original bequest.
    - Friedländer, Paul, Notes on "Kurt Riezler.", 334.; (1p., 1 leaf; two copies). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Anthologia lyrica., 335.; (5 items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Barja's Libros., 336.; (3 CF items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Beyer, Die pompejanische Wanddekoration I.1, Den Haag: Martinus Nijhoff, s.a. (prospectus)., 337.; (4 items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from "Bibliothek Paul Friedländer.", 338.; (7 items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Ford's Old Spanish Readings., 339.; (CF: 11pp.). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Friedländer's Herakles., 340.; (9 items, 14 leaves). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Friedländer's Johannes., 341.; (5 items). (Box 2)
      See also no.425.
    - Removed from Friedländer's Offprints,., 1932-1935; 342.; (4 items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Friedländer's Platon., 343.; (5 items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Friedländer's Rhythmen., 344.; (19 items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Gundolf s Caesar., 345.; (3 items, 4pp.) [missing]. (Box 2)
    - Removed from Luquiens's Introduction., 346.; (9 CF items). (Box 2)
    - Removed from Radt's review of Irigoin., 347.; (Offprint) (box 3) (3 leaves). (Box 2)
- Non-classical manuscripts
  - [Friedländer, Paul], "Athens, Agora" etc., 348.; (32 leaves). (Box 3)
  - Cancelled., 349. (Box 3)
  - [Friedländer, Paul], Miscellaneous notes on Nonnos., 350.; (479 pieces). (Box 3)
    See also removed to Correspondence, Königliche Bibliothek Berlin, Königliches Provinzial-Schulkollegium, and J. Mewaldt, to Friedländer.
  - Hinrichs, Gustav, review: W. Christ, Zur Chronologie des altgriechischen Epos., 351.; (Manuscript). (Box 3)
    Removed from Christ's Zur chronologie der altgriechischen Epos p.54 sq.; removed to Correspondence, Kranz, W. (1950).
  - Hinske, Norbert, Menschsein und Tapferkeit. Zur Interpretation des Platonischen Dialogs Laches, Typescript dissertation,., 1966; 352.; (36pp.). (Box 3)
    Removed to Correspondence, Kytzler, Bernhard, to [Paul] Friedländer, June 1, 1967. Typed letter signed (1p., 1 leaf).
  - [Wilamowitz File (box 3):]
    - --Cutting, obituary with photograph of Marie v. Wilamowitz-Moellendorff., 353. (Box 3)
    - --Cutting showing Wilamowitz lecturing at 100th anniversary of Mommsen's birth, associated, perhaps wrongly, with envelope postmarked., December 5, 1931; 354. (Box 3)
    - --Ecce der Landeschule zur Pforte., 1931; 355.; (Inscribed by W. K(ranz)]. (Box 3)
    - --Drawing of Wilamowitz (inscribed on verso "Herr Dr. Friedländer")., 356. (Box 3)
    - --Pförtner Blätter 6.1, Weihnachten., 1931; 357.; (including obituary of Wilamowitz with plate). (Box 3)
    - --Photograph of Wilamowitz (W. Höffert)., 358. (Box 3)
    - --Photograph of Wilamowitz (Franz Kullrich)., 359. (Box 3)
    - --Photograph of Wilamowitz-bust, 360.; (3 views). (Box 3)
    - --"Rede am Sarge von Ulrich von Wilamowitz-Moellendorff am Montag, dem 28. .", September 1931; 361. (Box 3)
    - --"Udalrico de Wilamowitz-Moellendorff octogenario.", 362.; (Broad sheet). (Box 3)
- Manuscripts of Paul and Charlotte Friedländer
  - Bound
    - [Arend, Walter.] "Das Trunkene Shier," illustrated typescript, with envelope addressed to Charlotte Friedländer., 363. (Box 4)
    - [Boehringer, Robert?], Brentano., 364. (Box 4)
      (Removed from [Paul Friedländer?], Poetry notebook, incipit: "Der Kreis Der Liebe," above) (Box 5).
    - Boehringer, Robert, "Eros und Tod dem andenken Rudolf Burckhardts.", 365. (Box 4)
      (Removed from [Paul Friedländer?], Poetry notebook, incipit: "Der Kreis Der Liebe," below) (Box 5).
    - [Boehringer, Robert?], Maximin., 366. (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?]. Notebook: Kulturgeschichte (Box 8)., 367. (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?] Poetry notebook., 368. (Box 4)
      Incipit: "Der Kreis Der Liebe" (January 1915).
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?] Poetry notebook., 369. (Box 4)
      Incipit: "Gebet. Kam mir erinnerung jener frühlingsstrassen" (Box 7).
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?] Poetry notebook., 370. (Box 4)
      Incipit: "I. Ich forschte bleichen eifers nach dem horte" (Box 7).
    - [Friedländer, Paul?] Commonplace book., 371. (Box 4)
      Incipit: "Aus den Sonetten an Orpheus" (Box 4).
    - [Friedländer, Paul?] Poetry notebook., 372. (Box 4)
      Incipit: "Dies ist ein Lied für Dick allein" (March 8, 1914), accompanied by loose sheet (incipit: "Mit Schatten wandeln essen trinken" (Box 8).
  - Unbound
    - "Aus "Sinn und Form", 7. Jg. 1955, H. 5 Friedrich Hölderin, Die Friedensfeier.", 373.; (4 leaves). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte, copyist] Hymnus zur Complet am Freitag., 374.; (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 4)
    - Friedländer, Charlotte, "Kunstgeschichte.", 375.; (2 leaves, folded) (box 8). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?] "La connaissance de Platon.", 376.; (six leaves + cover). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?] "Nachtphantasien.", 377.; (8pp., 2 leaves). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?], "O Macar ée! les demi-dieux enfants.", 378.; (1p.). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Charlotte?] "Wir sind die anderen, eine Parabel.", 379.; (2pp., 1 leaf). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Paul?], [Original verse, November 19, 1915-December 10. 1916; s.a.], 380.; (12 leaves + two blank). (Box 4)
      (Removed from [Paul Friedländer, Poetry notebook, incipit: "Der Kreis Der Liebe," above).
    - [Friedländer, Paul?] "Hören wir die Gläser klingen," 1933/4, 381.; (1 leaf). (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Paul, copyist?], "Niobe (Phalange, second moitie de 1846 & 1847.", 382.; Typescript. (Box 4)
    - [Friedländer, Paul?, copyist.] "Omar Khayyam.", 383.; (4pp., 1 sheet). (Box 4)
    - "Lastwort das Chabakkuk der Künder schauend empfing" (übersetzung von Buber)., 384.; Typescript (6pp., 6 leaves). (Box 4)
    - Removed from Rilke's Duineser Elegien., 385.; (1 item, 5pp.). (Box 4)
    - Unknown copiest in grey folder: removed to Correspondence, ----, Iula, to [Char]Iotte [Friedländer],., June 13, 1915; 386.; Autograph letter signed (2pp., 2 leaves). (Box 4)
    - "Das Lied des Bettlers.", 386a. (Box 4)
    - Hartleben, Otto Erich., 386b. (Box 4)
    - Hauptmann, Gerhart, "Die Klosteruhr.", 386c. (Box 4)
    - Morgenstern., 386d. (Box 4)
    - Perls, Richard., 386e. (Box 4)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria, Das Buch der Bilder (extracts)., 386f. (Box 4)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria, Die frühen Gedichte (extracts)., 386g. (Box 4)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria, "Erineerung.", 386h. (Box 4)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria, "Herbst.", 386i. (Box 4)
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria, "Mädchenmelancholie.", 386j. (Box 4)
    - Rilke, Rainer Mari, "Zum Einschlafen zu sagen.", 386k. (Box 4)
    - Roten, Graf August von., 386l. (Box 4)
  - Unbound Manuscripts and Miscellanea
    - [Friedländer, Paul] Fragment of Address book, B - C., 387.; (2 leaves). (Box 5)
    - [Friedländer, Paul] List of recipients for Platon III accompanied by envelope from "CARE/USA.", 388. (Box 5)
    - [Friedländer, Paul] Miscellaneous fragments, 389.; (8pp., 2 leaves). (Box 5)
      (incipit: (a) "Castigllioni Epica Nonniana" (b) "Clark Library" (c) "Edm Dickinson's" (d) "E?oµ ? ? ?," (e) "In Untversitati," (0 "Lesley" (g) "p.76" (h) "a?a?s???t??."
    - [Friedländer, Paul] Remarks for meeting of the Academic Senate, University of California,., April 15, 1948; 390.; (5 leaves). (Box 5)
    - [Friedländer, Paul], "Specialization and Universality,"., May 13, 1956; 391.; Typescript (20pp., 20 leaves), with two programs for the "Third Annual Initiation of The Cate Chapter, the Cum Laude Society" (Carpinteria, California: The Cate School, 1956). (Box 5)
    - [Friedländer, Paul]. Summary of Couch chapter 2., 392.; (6 leaves). (Box 5)
    - [Friedländer, Paul]. Summary of Schadewaldt, Wolfgang, 393.; (5p., 5 leaves). (Box 5)
    - [Friedländer, Paul]. Summary of Schuhl, Pierre-Maxime, Platon et I'art de son temps)., 394.; Typescript (6pp., 6 leaves). (Box 5)
    - Library call slip, completed by P. Friedländer,., March 19, 1919; 395. (Box 5)
    - [George, Stefan]., 396. (Box 5)
    - "Istituto italiano di studi Germanici... una celebrazioni di Stefan George,". s.a., April 17; 396a.; (3pp., 1 leaf). (Box 5)
    - "A la Société des Etudes allemandes. Oeuvres de Stefan George.", 396b.; (Cutting). (Box 5)
    - Ivory tongue-shaped bookmark with metal top with design., 396c. (Box 5)
    - Goethe file (Box 9)., 397. (Box 5)
    - [Guppy, Robert F.], "Kircher's Specimen of Pindar.", 398.; Typescript 14pp. (box 3). (Box 5)
      See also PF box 1.
    - [Guppy, Robert F.?], "Appendix: Actual tuning of kithara.", 399.; Typescript 6pp. (box 3). (Box 5)
    - "Zu Daniel Sennert.", 400.; (2pp. taped together). (Box 5)
  - Newspaper Cuttings
    - [Borchardt, Rudolf.] "Volterra aus der Rudolf Borchardt-Monographie von Werner Kraft.", 401. (Box 5)
      Removed from Radt's review of Irigoin.
    - Brueckner, Alfred, "Feuilleton. Wann ist der Altar von Pergamon errichtet worden?.", 402.; (Cutting). (Box 5)
    - [Bultmann, R., removed from envelope.] Eight cuttings, (Box ---)., ca. July 21-23, 1966; 403. (Box 5)
    - [Cheops.] "Eine Bestteigung der Cheopspyramide.", 404.; (Cutting). (Box 5)
    - Curtius, Ernst Robert, "Verständigung. Offener Brief an einen Franzosen" Voss Zeitung,., November 14, 1925; 405.; Cutting (box 2). (Box 5)
      Removed from Correspondence, s.u. Curtius, E.R., September 29, s.a.
    - Curtius, Ernst Robert, "Indezente und laszive Bücher" Die Literarische Welt no.16., [1926]; 406.; p.7, cutting (box 2). (Box 5)
      Removed from Correspondence, s.u. Curtius, E.R., September 29, sa.
    - Friedländer, Paul, [Letter to O'Ren] The Sun, Baltimore, (cutting), with The Sun (cutting)., July 30, 1940 April 26, 1940; 407. (Box 5)
    - [Frost, Robert.] Kessler, Jascha, "Frost: Plain Poetry about Life" Los Angeles Times Calendar., July 4, 1965; 408. (Box 5)
    - [Gundolf, Friedrich.] Valentin, Veit, "Friedrich der Grosse" (cutting)., 409. (Box 5)
    - [Gundolf, Friedrich.] Vietor, Karl, "Gundolfs Werk" (cutting)., 410. (Box 5)
      (Removed from Gundolf's Caesar, box 7).
    - [Heidegger, Martin.] Frankfurter Zeitung., November 27, 1936 and December 8, 1936; 411. (Box 5)
      Associated with Correspondence: Meyerhoff, Hilde and Hans, to [Paul] Friedländer, s.a., and Heidegger, Martin, to Paul Friedländer, s.a. (Box ---).
    - [Jacobsthal, Paul.] Möbius, H., "Zur Erinnerung an den Archäologen Paul Jacobsthal" [cutting from Frankfurt newspaper]., 412. (Box 5)
      Removed from Offprints, Anon., "Archaeological News" Archaeology 9, 1956, pp.215-221.
    - [Mommsen Theodor.] "Galerie deutscher Geistesführer. I. Theodor Mommsen.", 413.; (Cutting). (Box 5)
    - Neumann, Carl, "Bernhard Erdmannsdörffer. Zum 100. Geburtstag" Das Anderfaldüngblatt,., January 22, 1933; 414. (Box 5)
    - Proben und Berichte,., 15, 1961; 415. (Box 5)